First, use a rectangular tool to click on the 2D window to create a template.
Long press the W key, click on the template in the 3D window to add a fixed needle.
First, I will introduce the basic use of the sewing tool for everyone.
Select the sewing tool in the tool bar in the 3D window.
Then you can click on two points on the template in the 3D window to create a false needle.
After simulation, we can notice that the two points of the added false needle are sewn together.
We can observe the false needle thread in the 2D window.
After we select the false needle thread, we can adjust the length of the false needle thread in the attribute editor.
Then the false needle thread in the 3D window will change to the length of the set value.
Next, I will introduce the specific use of the false needle thread through a few cases.
For this purpose, I prepared a hat file in advance.
Select the false needle tool and add a false needle on both sides of the hat.
In addition to being able to add a false needle in the 3D window, we can also add a false needle in the 2D window.
Of course, since the length of the false needle has not yet been adjusted, the two sides of the hat will be sewn together automatically.
So after selecting the false needle thread, you can set the length for it.
When setting the length, if the false needle thread is on the same piece of sheet, the length of the false needle thread is absolute.
If it is the false needle thread on two pieces of sheet,
please refer to the specific length in the 3D window to adjust.
After the length of the false needle thread is shortened, the length of the false needle thread in the 3D window will be shortened,
so the two sides of the hat will be pulled up.
If the length of the false needle thread is constantly shortened, the part of the added false needle will be pulled together.
If the length of the false needle thread is too short, the part of the added false needle will be pulled together.
We can edit the false needle thread in the 2D window, and we can also edit the false needle thread in the 3D window.
We can also edit the false needle thread in the 3D window.
However, when moving the false needle thread in the 3D window,
it is necessary to pay attention that the false needle thread will be absorbed on the top plate of the camera angle when moving.
Therefore, in some cases, it will be more accurate to adjust the false needle thread in the 2D window.
In addition to the false needle thread tool, there are also tools for fixing it to the virtual model.
Fixed to the virtual model can make the false needle thread fixed to the model at one end,
so the plate will not fall down easily.
Click on the false needle thread on the clothing creation panel.
If the clothing becomes transparent, it means that the creation is successful.
You can start clicking on the false needle thread on the model.
You can use the false needle thread on the 3D window to adjust the model and the false needle thread on the clothing.
But if you use the fixed to the virtual model,
it is not possible to adjust the false needle thread position in the 2D window.
Similarly, we can also set the length of the false needle thread between the virtual model and the clothing.
You can set the length of the false needle thread between the virtual model and the clothing.
Next is the second small case.
We can notice that it is bent in the part of the collar.
Use the false needle thread on the clothing to fix it to the bent part.
But now the part of the collar is bent,
so we need to use the edited sewing tool to adjust the position of the false needle thread to make it more natural.
The first thing that occurs is that the false needle thread is not fixed firmly on the clothing.
It can be adjusted by checking the position of the bottom of the clothing.
You can notice that the position is closer to the bottom of the clothing.
You can now adjust the position of the bottom of the clothing to the right of the work.
In addition to being able to separated manually,
the use of the edited sewing tool is also possible.
Use a sewing machine to set the length, and use a sewing machine to hold the two sides together.
But the current length is too long, so you need to shorten it to make the bottom more natural.
In addition to opening the clothing, you can also tighten the clothing.
After adding a seam on the left and right sides, set the seam line length again and tighten it.
You can use a sewing machine to fix the seam line on the left side.
Adjust the position of the seam line.
The point is to save 1 cm of sewing법
And Wat is 2 cm away from the position of one часть.
Nad is redish, red, and large.
Now he's in a dress.
Wait a minute.
Give him a red, brown, and yellow.
There's a big gap here.
For Hemlock.
需要调整甲缝线长度,避免拉伸。
接下来是最后一个小案例。
首先使用固定到虚拟模特上工具,在裙子底摆添加甲缝,再点击虚拟模特手指添加甲缝。
为了避免腰带部位受到影响,可以先将其冷冻起来。
然后使用编辑甲缝工具点击甲缝线,不断缩短线的长度,避免一次收缩过多造成服装不稳定。
继续缩短甲缝线。
一边完成之后,我们可以使用同样的方法将另一边提起。
我们试试看如果一次性收缩服装会是什么样子。
裙子容易被拉扯变形,产生不稳定,所以建议使用之前的方法去调整部分裙子会更加稳定。
使用编辑甲缝工具调整甲缝的位置。
使用编辑甲缝的位置。
在调整完成后,导入我们提前制作好的姿势文件,或者导入同样的模型为Morph Target,改变模特、姿势。
我们就可以看到裙子的模型。
编辑甲缝的形态也随角色姿势发生了变化。
调整甲缝的位置,解决服装与手指的穿插。
Thank you.
You